Email: reubenjacob16@gmail.com

Mobile: +919686570567

Website: https://reubenojacob.github.io/index.html
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/reubenojacob

AIM

Looking for an entry level position in the Software Development area in a Reputed Company.

SUMMARY

Graduate Engineer in Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering from Ramaiah Institute of Technology, Bangalore, 2020 batch. Project, Internship, and co-curricular activity experience consists of core and interdisciplinary work in **control systems, computer science, embedded systems, and micro-controllers**.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, HTML, Verilog

Software: MS Office, Arduino, Energia, Matlab, PSpice, Multisim, Rockwell Automation Software, Mission Planner

Exposure: Angular, JavaScript, CSS, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Pandas, KNN, AWS

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Apr. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Student Research Assistant

Bangalore, Karnataka

Project assistant for a department project.

Published author in noted Springer journal Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing (AISC) Series.

Li2 Technologies

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

Student Intern

Bangalore, Karnataka

Worked on the development of an IoT focused on assistive rehabilitation.

• National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences

July 2019 - Aug. 2019

Student Intern

Bangalore, Karnataka

Biomedical Engineering internship involving the calibration, assessment, and study of medical equipment as part of the medical electronics team of NIMHANS.

Edhitha Unmanned Aerial Systems

Bangalore, Karnataka

Lead Navigation Engineer

Dec 2017- Aug 2018

Lead Navigation Engineer representing Edhitha for the <u>AUVSI SUAS 2018</u> held in Maryland, USA.

Lead the team to achieve rank 10 internationally.

Associate Developer: Mechanical and Instrumentation Engineering

Sep 2017-Dec 2017

Associate Engineering Developer for mechanical design and navigational control systems.

EDUCATION

Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2020

B.E Electronics and Instrumentation CGPA 8.1/10

Dalla' Dalla Calaaa

Delhi Public School Bangalore East

Mar. 2014 - Mar. 2016

All India Senior School Certificate Examination.

Overall Percentage: 87.4

Delhi Public School East

Mar. 2014

All India Secondary School Examination.

PROJECTS

IoT Based Wearable Tachycardia Monitoring System Using Machine Learning

Mar. 2020-Aug.2020

Wearable IoT based health monitoring system which continuously pings data to a web server where medical data is stored and evaluated using K-Means Clustering algorithms.

Self-Balancing Cycle with Location Tracking

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

An autonomous self-balancing cycle capable of static balancing using inertial measurements and a flywheel controlled by a micro-controller. System also provides location tracking using GPS and GSM for extended safety facilities.

GPS location tracker with SOS capabilities

Apr. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Portable handheld location tracking device capable of continuous tracking with an online database using IOT with various modes of usage.

Unmanned Aerial System

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2018

Unmanned aerial drone capable of autonomous flight and navigation, automatic take-off and landing, air drop and image capture.

Wearable smartwatch with Blood Pressure Alert

Apr. 2017 - June. 2017

Wearable smartwatch with a real time clock, pulse sensor and blood pressure alert.

Automatic Home Gardening System

Apr. 2017 - June. 2017

Automatic home gardening system capable of controlled irrigation with specific timing and water volume options.

AWARDS

Best Project Award

Aug. 2020

Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Best Project in the Department of Electronics and Instrumentation, Batch 2020

• International Rank 10 in the 16th AUVSI SUAS Competition

June 2018

Students Unmanned Aerial Association

Placed 10th Internationally in the 16th AUVSI Student SUAS competition platform, held in Maryland USA, where almost 200 international teams annually build, demonstrate, and compete with UAS systems capable of various Mission requirements.

International Rank 99 in the International English Olympiad

Jan. 2013

ACTIVITIES

Ramaiah Tech Fest

Oct. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Lead Organizer

U&I Teaching Foundation

Dec. 2019 - Mar. 2020

Teaching Volunteer

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

• Sports Oct. 2016 - July 2020

College Badminton Team Bodybuilding

Music

Trinity Qualified Musician (Keyboard) Grade 3